[
    {
        "question": "The Centre has transferred assorted subsidies and sops to the beneficiaries through the Direct Benefit Transfer (DBT) worth about Rs___ so far in the current financial year.",
        "options": [
            "Rs 4.15 lakh crore ",
            "Rs 3.26 lakh crore ",
            "Rs 2.97 lakh crore ",
            "Rs 1.78 lakh crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 4.15 lakh crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has announced a $1 million reward for anyone who deciphers the Indus Valley script?",
        "options": [
            "Kerala  ",
            "Tamil Nadu  ",
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Tamil Nadu  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true about veteran nuclear scientist Rajagopala Chidambaram, who recently passed away?",
        "options": [
            "He was instrumental in India\u2019s nuclear tests of 1975 (Smiling Buddha) and 1998 (Pokhran-II). ",
            "He was honored with Padma Shri (1975) & Padma Vibhushan (1999). ",
            "He served as Principal Scientific Adviser (2001\u20132018) ",
            "All are correct "
        ],
        "answer": "All are correct ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The world\u2019s oldest person Tomiko Itooka has died aged 116. She was from which country",
        "options": [
            "Spain ",
            "Sweden ",
            "France ",
            "Japan "
        ],
        "answer": "Japan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank is merging with National Co-operative Bank as approved by the RBI?",
        "options": [
            "Maratha Sahakari Bank ",
            "Cosmos Co-operative Bank ",
            "Sahebrao Deshmukh Sahakari Bank D) Karnataka Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Unknown",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Omkareshwar Floating Solar Project is inaugurated in which state recently?",
        "options": [
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Himachal Pradesh  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Manipur "
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "World's largest floating solar project, is to be constructed in which of the following Indian State/UTs?",
        "options": [
            "Daman and Diu ",
            "Pondicherry ",
            "Madhya Pradesh ",
            "Gujarat "
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The World's largest Floating solar energy project is to be constructed at Omkareshwar dam.This will be a  _ solar power plant.",
        "options": [
            "600 MW ",
            "500 MW ",
            "200 MW ",
            "700 MW "
        ],
        "answer": "600 MW ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first male football player to be honoured with the US Presidential Medal of Freedom Award?",
        "options": [
            "Lionel Messi ",
            "Cristiano Ronaldo ",
            "Luka Modri\u0107 ",
            "Robert Lewandowski "
        ],
        "answer": "Lionel Messi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the highest civilian award of the United States of America?",
        "options": [
            "Achievement Medal ",
            "Meritorious Service Medal ",
            "Commendation Medal ",
            "Presidential Medal of Freedom Award "
        ],
        "answer": "Presidential Medal of Freedom Award ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the new deadline for implementing the transaction volume cap on UPI apps as per NPCI?",
        "options": [
            "December 31, 2025 ",
            "December 31, 2026 ",
            "December 31, 2027 ",
            "December 31, 2028 "
        ],
        "answer": "December 31, 2026 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Bank for Financing Infrastructure and Development (NaBFID) has invested Rs 745 crore in long-term bonds issued by NDR InvIT. Who sponsors NDR InvIT?",
        "options": [
            "has invested Rs 745 ",
            "India Ratings ",
            "CARE Ratings ",
            "Reserve Bank of India ",
            "NDR Warehousing Private Limited ",
            "have partnered to launch UPI payments in "
        ],
        "answer": "Reserve Bank of India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which guidelines have VFS Capital applied for a small finance bank licence?",
        "options": [
            "\u2018Greenfield\u2019 Bank Licensing Guidelines ",
            "\u2018Rural Finance\u2019 Bank Licensing Guidelines ",
            "\u2018Financial Inclusion\u2019 Bank Licensing Scheme ",
            "\u2018On-tap\u2019 Licensing Scheme for SFBs in the Private Sector "
        ],
        "answer": "\u2018On-tap\u2019 Licensing Scheme for SFBs in the Private Sector ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following small savings schemes has an interest rate of 8.2% for the January-March 2025 quarter?",
        "options": [
            "Kisan Vikas Patra ",
            "National Savings Certificate ",
            "Public Provident Fund ",
            "Sukanya Samriddhi Account "
        ],
        "answer": "Sukanya Samriddhi Account ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following interest rate on small savings scheme is not correct under the January to March quarter of financial year 2025-2026?",
        "options": [
            "Senior Citizen Savings Scheme \u2013 8.2% ",
            "National Savings Certificate \u2013 7.7% ",
            "Public Provident Fund Scheme \u2013 7.4%% ",
            "Sukanya Samriddhi Account \u2013 8.2% "
        ],
        "answer": "Public Provident Fund Scheme \u2013 7.4%% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The interest rate on Kisan Vikas Patra for January to March quarter of financial year 2025-2026 is set at 7.5 percent. What is the maturity period of this scheme?",
        "options": [
            "125 months ",
            "120 months ",
            "115 months ",
            "128 months "
        ],
        "answer": "115 months ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Union Bank of India has enhanced its Digital Rupee (e\u20b9) application with accessibility features, marking a significant step in digital inclusion. What is the Digital Rupee (e\u20b9)?",
        "options": [
            "A cryptocurrency ",
            "A type of foreign exchange ",
            "A prepaid gift card ",
            "A digital version of fiat currency "
        ],
        "answer": "A digital version of fiat currency ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has launched FedOne, a new transaction banking platform powered by Nucleus Software\u2019s FinnAxia solution?",
        "options": [
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Federal Bank  ",
            "Bank of Baroda "
        ],
        "answer": "Federal Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chairman and Managing Director (CMD) of the Food Corporation of India (FCI)?",
        "options": [
            "of the Food Corporation ",
            "Dheeraj Sharma  ",
            "Manoj Kumar  ",
            "Ashutosh Agnihotri ",
            "Rahul Singh "
        ],
        "answer": "Manoj Kumar  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Secretary of the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI)?",
        "options": [
            "Devajit Saikia ",
            "Prabhtej Singh Bhatia ",
            "Jay Shah ",
            "Rahul Dravid "
        ],
        "answer": "Devajit Saikia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Punjab & Sind Bank will launch an instant loan scheme for the MSME sector. What is the maximum loan amount under the instant loan scheme for the MSME sector by Punjab & Sind Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 10 lakh ",
            "Rs 20 lakh ",
            "Rs 25 lakh ",
            "Rs 50 lakh "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 25 lakh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of its stake in Unity Small Finance Bank does BharatPe plan to sell?",
        "options": [
            "25% ",
            "49% ",
            "51% ",
            "33% "
        ],
        "answer": "25% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Union Shipping Ministry has proposed new additions to the \u20b972,000-crore mega-infrastructure project in which Island?",
        "options": [
            "Barren Island ",
            "Rutland Island ",
            "Narcondam Island ",
            "Great Nicobar Island "
        ],
        "answer": "Great Nicobar Island ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been re-elected as the Speaker of the House of Representatives?",
        "options": [
            "Andy Biggs ",
            "Lauren Boebert ",
            "Christopher A. Wray ",
            "Mike Johnson "
        ],
        "answer": "Mike Johnson ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \"Wild Fictions : Essays\"?",
        "options": [
            "Amitabh Ghosh ",
            "Aravind Adiga ",
            "Vikram Seth ",
            "Ruskin Bond "
        ],
        "answer": "Amitabh Ghosh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city has been declared the world\u2019s most polluted with PM2.5 levels peaking at 266 \u00b5g/m\u00b3?",
        "options": [
            "Hanoi ",
            "Beijing ",
            "New Delhi ",
            "Jakarta "
        ],
        "answer": "Hanoi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian state is being monitored for the first cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) by ICMR?",
        "options": [
            "Kerala ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Karnataka "
        ],
        "answer": "Karnataka ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state launched the Shahid Madho Singh Haath Kharcha Scheme for tribal students during the Adivasi Mela?",
        "options": [
            "Jharkhand ",
            "Odisha ",
            "Chhattisgarh ",
            "Madhya Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Odisha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country ranks first globally in terms of cyberattacks in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "China ",
            "Russia ",
            "United States ",
            "India "
        ],
        "answer": "United States ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian state faces significant human trafficking challenges, particularly in the Sundarbans region, due to socio-environmental vulnerabilities?",
        "options": [
            "Odisha ",
            "Bihar ",
            "West Bengal ",
            "Assam "
        ],
        "answer": "West Bengal ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state is the Soreng District where the country's first organic fisheries cluster has been inaugurated recently?",
        "options": [
            "Manipur  ",
            "Nagaland  ",
            "Sikkim  ",
            "Arunachal Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Sikkim  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state is the country\u2019s first natural pearl cluster notified by the Department of Fisheries,government of India ?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar  ",
            "Jharkhand  ",
            "Chhattisgarh  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Jharkhand  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which financial institution will provide financial and other assistance to the development of organic fisheries clusters in Soreng District of Sikkim?",
        "options": [
            "IRDAI  ",
            "SEBI ",
            "SIDBI  ",
            "NABARD "
        ],
        "answer": "NABARD ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Pradhan Mantri Matsya Sampada Yojana (PMMSY):  1. It will be implemented over a period of 5 years from FY 2020-21 to FY 2024-25 in all States/Union Territories.  2. More than 50% of the total estimated investment of the PMMSY is earmarked for creation and up-gradation of fisheries infrastructure facilities.  3. The scheme plans to reduce post-harvest losses from the present high of 25% to about 10% by modernizing and strengthening value chain.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "1 and 3 only ",
            "3 only "
        ],
        "answer": "1 and 3 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the 11th Chairman of the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)?",
        "options": [
            "K. Radhakrishnan ",
            "K. Kasturirangan ",
            "Shailesh Nayak ",
            "V Narayanan "
        ],
        "answer": "V Narayanan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]